The crime site and his residence may be within walking distance
案发现场及凶手住址
between the point she went missing and the victim's home.
和受害者的失踪地点、家庭住址 可能只有步行距离
I think I found the place.
我可能找到地方了
Wait for me.
等我
Cho Hyun-gil!
赵贤吉
If you search his house, it will be neatly organized.
如果搜查其房间 陈设会非常整齐
The weapon he used will also have been put away neatly.
凶器也会整齐放置
That's not a shelf. It's the interior floor of the fridge.
那个不是架子 是冰箱内壁
Captain Yoon. What…
尹组长 怎么了？
Captain Yoon.
尹组长
It's caked with dust. I doubt he'll come back.
屋里全是灰 应该不回来了吧？
A man who lives alone doesn't clean.
独居男人不会打扫的
But seeing how organized and neat he was,
不过看他那么整洁爱干净
he probably spends a lot of time cleaning too.
应该也花了不少时间打扫
Seeing how dusty it is like Captain Kook said,
像国组长所说积了那么厚的灰
he didn't come here for a long time.
说明他已经很久没回来了
But…
不过…
we'll still wait for him.
我们会在这里等他的
I'll wait too.
我一起等
You don't have to.
不用麻烦你了
-Detective Nam and I can handle it. -Yes.
-有南刑警和我就够了 -好
Then I'll get going first.
那我就先回去了
Goodnight. I'll see you around.
晚安 再见了
Bye.
再见
You should go too.
你也回去吧
I don't want there to be a pile of cars here.
我不想让这里停着一堆车
I'll park my car somewhere else.
我会把我的车停到别处去
What?
什么？
He never listens to others.
他从来不听别人的话
He doesn't.
确实
Good luck.
辛苦你们了
If anything happens, give me a call right away.
如果有事 马上给我打电话
Get some sleep if you're tired.
累了就睡会儿吧
No. I'm fine.
不 我没事
If you're tired, you can get some sleep.
你累了的话 可以睡会儿
No. I'm good too.
不用 我也没事
Should I get out?
要我出去看看吗？
Wait.
等等
Darn it.
该死
That scared the wits out of me.
把我魂都吓飞了
Do you carry around cat food?
你还随身带了猫粮吗？
Yes. Sometimes.
是 偶尔会带
It's not cat food. It's just some snacks.
这不是猫粮 这是零食
What are you eating?
你吃的什么？
Chocolate.
巧克力
I see.
知道了
I'm good.
我不吃
I didn't peg you
我没想到
to be an animal lover.
你这么喜欢小动物
Animals can't talk,
动物们不会说话
so they can't lie.
所以不会撒谎
Even when they're hungry
就算它们饿了
or sick, they can't tell us.
或者病了 也不能跟我们说
So I just thought
所以我只是觉得
it'd be nice
如果人能够
if someone recognized it first.
先一步察觉该有多好
What are you doing here so early in the morning?
大早上的你们在这儿干什么呢？
Oh, hello.
哦 你好
We're just waiting for someone.
我们在等人
Are you waiting for Cho?
姓赵那个？
Well, yes.
是的
Do you know Mr. Cho Hyun-gil?
你认识赵贤吉吗？
I'm his landlady.
我是他房东
Do you happen to know when he'll be back?
你知道他什么时候回来吗？
I actually came here to check because I couldn't reach him.
我来这里就是看他回来没 因为我联系不上他
He's behind on rent,
他欠我房租
but I can't get hold of him.
可是我找不到他
Well, anyway…
那个…
Why are you looking for him so early in the morning?
你们大早上找他干吗？
We're from the police.
我们是警察
SCIENTIFIC INVESTIGATIONS
（科学调查小组）
-You're here. -Hey.
-你来了 -你好
The description of the little girl the landlady saw
房东对她看到的小女孩的描述
matches that of Soo-hyun.
符合秀贤的特征
-Did you check the vehicle too? -Yes.
-你检查车了吗？ -检查过了
Now, we just need to find Cho Hyun-gil.
现在我们只要找到赵贤吉就行了
Sir, you're here.
你来了
Hey, what are you doing here? Darn it.
喂 你来干什么？该死
Hey, the Behavioral Analysis Team can't be here.
喂 犯罪行为分析小组不能来这里
-Why not? -You know the answer.
-为什么不能？ -你知道的
You're supposed to investigate under the table.
你们要秘密调查
If the higher-ups find out, they'll go nuts.
如果被上边的发现 他们会气疯的
And the media shouldn't know.
媒体也不能知道
This is so unfair.
这也太过分了
Why is it unfair?
过分什么过分？
Don't you know the commissioner is more afraid of reporters than his wife?
你难道不知道厅长怕记者 比怕老婆还厉害？
What? You're here too?
什么？你怎么也来了？
I'm sure Soo-hyun's fingers are around his house.
我确定秀贤的手指就在他房子附近
We must find them.
我们一定要找出来
First, you'll have to help us search the scene.
首先 你要帮我们搜查现场
Gosh.
天啊
Check that spot over there.
检查一下那边
This spot here?
这边吗？
Careful. Be careful not to touch that.
小心别碰到那个了
Check that spot in the back too.
后边也检查一下
Anything?
找到什么了吗？
Did you find anything? Look over there.
你找到什么了吗？看那边
Over here!
这里
What is it?
什么东西？
It's decomposed, but it is a child's finger.
已经腐烂了 不过确实是儿童的手指
Let's keep searching.
继续搜
There are only eight.
只有八个
Let's keep looking.
继续找
I'm sure we'll find the rest.
我们一定能把剩下的都找出来
They may have drifted away.
可能已经漂走了
Let's search together
大家沿着
all the way to the nearest sewer.
最近的下水道一起找
Let's keep on looking.
继续找吧
We'll search together.
大家一起找
We're missing two fingers of a girl!
我们还没找到女孩的另外两只手指
Look through the grass and check under the rocks.
找找草丛里 还有石头下边
Please search thoroughly!
请彻底搜查
-Yes, ma'am.
-好
Young-soo.
荣秀
Yes.
是
We searched thoroughly all the way there but found nothing.
我们一直搜到那里 什么都没找到
This is the last spot we can search.
这是最后一块地方了
-They must've rotted away by now. -The body was
-现在肯定早就腐烂了 -尸体
stored in the freezer before it was discarded at different times.
分别被丢弃之前在冰箱里冻着
The decomposition has probably been delayed.
可能不会腐烂那么快
We must find at least the bones.
我们至少要找到骨头
We still have hope, so let's keep on looking.
还有希望 请继续找吧
Let's search some more.
继续找吧
Yes, sir.
好
Captain.
组长
Did you find something?
你找到东西了？
Darn it. It's a sausage.
该死 是香肠
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
We checked the area around Cho Hyun-gil's home
案件发生后 我们在赵贤吉家
immediately after the incident broke out.
周围都搜过一遍
Right.
对
It didn't look like anyone lived there,
看着不像有人住过
so it was overlooked.
所以当时就没注意
No, it's totally understandable.
没事 完全可以理解
I couldn't even figure out where the entrance was.
我连入口在哪里都没发现
I couldn't even find the door.
我连门在哪儿都找不到
Why is it so hot in here? Am I the only one sweating?
这里怎么热成这样？ 就我一个人出汗了吗？
Here, use this as a fan.
给你 用这个当扇子吧
-Thanks. -Soo-hyun's fingers…
-谢谢 -秀贤的手指…
We'll find them.
我们会找到的
We already found eight of them. They were thrown out,
我们找到八个了 既然他都有地方扔
so we'll find the rest.
剩下的我们也能找到
Yes, we must find them.
对 一定要找到
Right.
对
So how did you know…
你怎么会知道…
that her fingers would be there?
她的手指在那里？
It was just…
就是…
a gut feeling.
直觉
You're as intuitive as Captain Yoon.
你和我们尹组长一样直觉很准
Why don't we call it a day?
今天就到此为止吧
Yes, let's do that.
对啊 就这样吧
You can all get going.
你们都回去吧
I'll leave in a bit.
我等会儿再走
It was a long day.
今天都辛苦了
Tomorrow will be another hard day. Get some rest.
明天还要继续辛苦 好好休息吧
I'm okay. You should all get going.
我没事 你们都回去吧
-All right. -Bye.
-好 -再见
Then I'll get going too.
那我也走了
Okay, good work today.
好 今天辛苦了
Take it easy.
辛苦了
Ha-young.
霞永
If you insist on staying all by yourself,
如果你坚持自己留在这儿
everyone else will feel like they're not working hard enough.
其他人会觉得自己好像不够勤奋
My apologies. That wasn't my intention.
抱歉 我不是那个意思
Don't overwork yourself.
别把自己累坏了
-I won't. Have a good night. -You too.
-不会的 慢走 -再见
-Take it easy. -Bye.
-辛苦了
My gosh. I'm sorry, honey.
天啊 对不起 亲爱的
I woke you up, didn't I?
吵醒你了吧？
Are the kids asleep?
孩子们都睡了吗？
I see.
这样啊
All right.
知道了
By the way, tell Joo-hyun and Soo-hyun…
对了 跟珠贤、秀贤说…
that I want to hear their voices.
我想听听她们的声音
Have them call me when they wake up.
等她们醒了让她们给我打电话
Oh, boy. I'm being selfish again.
真是的 我又只想着我自己
I woke you up.
我把你吵醒了
I'm sorry.
真抱歉
Go back to sleep, Mi-yeon.
接着睡吧 美妍
Okay.
好
Kidnapped on May 20.
5月20日被绑架
Body parts were found for the first time on May 29.
5月29日部分身体首次被发现
The torso and the head were also found on May 30.
5月30日躯干和头颅也被找到
On June 25, additional body parts were found in a toilet at a motel
6月25日在凶手待过一晚的旅馆
after the culprit spent a night there.
又发现部分身体
Cho Hyun-gil disposed of the body parts at different times and locations.
他在不同时间和地点抛弃尸块
Where are the two fingers…
另外两只还没找到的手指
that haven't turned up yet?
到底在哪里呢？
Where could Cho Hyun-gil be hiding?
赵贤吉会藏在哪里呢？
44 DAYS AFTER THE INCIDENT
（案发44天后）
JULY 12, 2000
（2000年7月12日）
FORENSICS SQUAD
（现场鉴定组）
-You're here. -Good work.
-你来了 -辛苦了
Where's In-tak?
仁卓呢？
He went to take a nap.
他去睡觉了
May I see the analysis result?
我可以看下分析结果吗？
Yes, one second.
好 稍等
Right here.
给你
-Hey. -You're here.
-唉唷 -你来了
I guess you had a rough night.
看来你晚上没睡好啊
I lied down to take a nap,
我躺下睡觉
but I kept having dreams of looking for the kid's fingers, so I just got up.
结果一直梦见找那孩子的手指头 干脆就起来了
You're doing good work.
真是辛苦你了
We checked the fingerprints we got yesterday from that house,
我们比对了昨天在房子里找到的指纹
and they're mostly of Cho Hyun-gil or the victim.
基本上不是赵贤吉的 就是受害儿童的
Have you heard about the DNA too?
你也听说DNA结果出来了吧？
Yes, the NFS called.
是 国科搜打过电话了
I don't see his middle and ring fingers here either.
我没看到他的中指和无名指
There were only three fingerprints on the weapon too.
凶器上也只有三根手指的指纹
The ones we found at his place are all partial.
我们在他家找到的指纹都是残缺的
All we have are only five fingers.
我们现在只有五根手指的记录
For now, we know that it was done by Cho Hyun-gil.
现在我们知道是赵贤吉干的了
We just have to find out where he's hiding.
只要找到他的藏身之处就行了
We found out who he is, so he'll be caught soon.
既然已经查到身份 很快就能抓到他
-Anyway, keep it up. -Okay.
-反正继续努力吧 -好
-Let me know if you find anything. -All right.
-有新消息通知我
-Take care. -Goodbye.
-辛苦了 -再见
Cho Hyun-gil. Age 40.
赵贤吉 40岁
He lived in 39-1 Changeui-dong.
住在彰义洞39之1号
He has a history of molesting a four-year-old girl in Songju-dong
曾在圣住洞猥亵四岁女童
in September of 1997.
是1997年9月的事
So how did he get omitted from the list?
那他怎么没在名单上？
After he moved, he did not register his new address.
搬家后 他没有注册新住址
That's why he was left out.
所以被漏掉了
I went to his house,
我去过他住的地方
and it could hardly be called a home
是一个根本无法满足
where one lives.
正常生活的居住环境
His house was on the outskirts,
他家在郊区
so we missed it when we went around.
所以搜查的时候遗漏了
I'm sorry.
真抱歉
We missed him when he was right there.
在眼皮子底下被漏掉了啊
Hey, wait.
等等
If he was previously convicted in 1997,
如果他是1997年被判的刑
it hasn't been that long.
这还没过多久啊
He was sentenced to two years and six months.
他被判了两年零六个月
He was released this March.
今年3月出狱
Goodness, that means it has only been four months.
天啊 就是说才过去四个月
The ink on the paperwork probably hasn't even dried, that jerk.
文件上的墨水估计还没干 这个混蛋
Anyway, the DNA of the missing kid was found in his house, right?
在他家找到了失踪儿童的DNA 对吧？
The NFS just called.
国科搜才打过电话
We also confirmed his fingerprints that were on the weapon.
我们也确认了凶器上的指纹就是他的
Make sure you find
你们一定
where this Cho Hyun-gil is.
要找到赵贤吉
If he did this only two months after his release,
如果他才放出来两个月就敢作案
we don't know what he'll do next.
我们根本不知道他还会做什么
Captain Yoon, let's hurry.
尹组长 要加快速度啊
The entire team went out to search around the Changeui-dong area.
整个团队都去彰义洞周边搜查了
I sent Detective Nam out to the butcher shop Cho worked at.
我派南刑警去了赵某工作过的肉铺
He must've worked here while Moon-soo was here.
肯定是文秀在的时候 他在这干过活
-Moon-soo? -He's my nephew.
-文秀？ -我侄子
I had some business to take care of,
我有些生意要处理
so my nephew was looking after my shop.
就让我侄子帮我看店
Oh, I see.
明白了
That man suddenly quit even before a month was up.
那个人还没干够一个月就突然辞职
Most people won't pay the man after leaving like that.
说不干就不干了 换做别人根本不会给他钱
I'm a good man, so I paid him what he deserves.
我是好人 所以才照样付给他了
Do you have anything to show that you paid him?
你有给他转账的记录吗？
You know, on your bank account history.
比如你的银行账单
People who take up jobs like this do it for the cash.
干这种活的人都是想拿现金才干的
You paid him fully in cash?
你是全部用现金给他支付的吗？
Right, I gave him some checks too.
对 我还给他付了支票
Yes, do you remember which bank it was?
好 你还记得是哪家银行吗？
Was it Johong Bank?
好像是朝洪银行？
May I see the transaction history of this check?
我可以看下这张支票的交易记录吗？
I guess we did the search when his nephew was at the shop.
我们调查的时候是他侄子在看店
That's why we missed him.
所以才错过了他
I'll send you the address of where the check was used.
我把支票兑现的地址发给你
-There are three fingerprints? -Yes.
-有三个指纹吗？ -是
When you grab a knife or a saw,
握刀子或锯子的时候
your fingerprints are left at a certain location.
指纹会留在特定的位置上
Like this.
像这样
I'd get it if we didn't find any fingerprints at all.
如果我们完全没发现指纹我可以理解
You'll see even partial prints from the middle and ring fingers.
可是能看到中指和无名指的部分指纹
Right thumb, right index, and right pinky.
右手拇指 右手食指还有右手小拇指
It's strange that those were the only prints.
很奇怪只有这些指纹
It's either one of the two.
应该有两个原因
He either has an odd grip…
他要么是握法奇特
or is missing fingers.
要么就是缺少手指
I'm going to make you fly.
我要让你飞起来
Here we go.
开始了
Just push me.
快推我
Don't do it so hard.
别推那么用力
By any chance, have you seen this man?
请问你见过这个男人吗？
Hey, have you seen this customer?
喂 你见过这个顾客没？
Could you please try to remember?
请帮忙回忆一下？
He used a check here on June 26.
他在6月26号时用过一张支票
I'm not sure about the date, but I remember getting a check.
我不确定日期 就记得收了张支票
I'd never received one before.
以前从来没收过
But…
不过…
I don't remember what he looked like.
我不记得他长什么样了
Do you have CCTV?
你们有监控吗？
He's only missing his right middle and ring fingers.
他只缺了右手中指和无名指
No matter how meticulously you plan something,
不管你计划得多么严谨
your habits come out like second nature.
习惯就像老朋友一样总会暴露出来
I'm sure there was a reason behind stripping her.
我敢肯定脱她衣服是有原因的
He had to strip her to get off.
他一定要把她衣服脱了心里才舒坦
And whoever did that is the real culprit.
那才是真正的凶手
-Gil-pyo. -Hey.
-吉票 -喂
The culprit.
凶手
He's probably missing two fingers, okay?
可能缺了两根手指 对吧？
Will you please stay quiet?
你能不能安静点？
The visitors who come to Seoul are over…
首尔的游客超过了…
How long will you treat us like a shadow?
你想无视我们到什么时候？
I didn't treat you like a shadow… What?
我没有无视你们…怎么回事？
You're banning a solid team from doing any work. What else is it then?
你现在让一个强大的团队无用武之地 这不是无视是什么？
What is it? Be honest. Something is going on, right?
怎么了？说实话 是不是有事？
No, nothing is going on.
没有 什么事都没有
Look at this.
看看啊
I can always tell when you're lying.
你撒谎的时候我一眼就能看出来
I know you.
我了解你
You can't fool me.
你骗不了我
Wait, one second.
等等
Okay.
对
-Stay here. I'll go. -Okay.
-别动 我去吧 -好
Hello.
你好
SOJU
（烧酒）
A pack of cigarettes, please.
拿包烟
That will be 3,200 won.
3200韩元
Wait.
等等
Is that him?
是他吗？
Your change is 1,800 won.
找零1800韩元
Thank you. Goodbye.
谢谢你 再见
What? The guy who just went out.
什么？这个人刚走
Just now?
刚走？
Yes, he looks like the man who just left.
对 他跟刚走的那个人长得一样
His clothes.
衣服一样
Is that him?
是他吗？
Mr. Cho Hyun-gil?
赵贤吉？
Darn it.
该死
Cho Hyun-gil!
赵贤吉
Captain Yoon.
尹组长
You're under emergency arrest for Lee Soo-hyun's murder.
你因涉嫌李秀贤谋杀案被紧急逮捕
You have the right to consult an attorney and to remain silent.
你有权咨询律师 也有权保持沉默
Do you have anything to say?
你还有什么话想说吗？
Darn it!
该死
-Are you okay, Il-young? -Yes.
-你还好吗 日永？ -没事
Chief Heo, we caught him.
许队长 我们抓住他了
We caught him!
我们抓住他了
-Cho Hyun-gil? -Yes.
-赵贤吉？ -是的
What about his fingers?
他的手指呢？
So you drank through the night on May 19,
所以你在5月19日晚喝了酒
then abducted Lee Soo-hyun
然后在次日下午3点左右
around 3 p.m. the next day.
绑架了李秀贤
Is that correct?
是这样吗？
Why was it Soo-hyun, a girl who was only five years old?
为什么选才五岁的小女孩李秀贤？
I just…
我只是…
saw that girl there.
看见那个女孩了
Are you saying it wasn't planned?
你是说这不是预谋杀人？
Did you kidnap Lee Soo-hyun,
你绑架李秀贤
so you could rape her?
是为了强奸她吗？
-No. -No?
-不是 -不是？
Cho Hyun-gil.
赵贤吉
You served time for molesting and assaulting a minor.
你曾因猥亵和侵犯未成年人入狱
And you were discharged in March.
3月出狱
It had only been two months.
才过了两个月
Right?
对吗？
Gosh, it hurts.
天啊 好疼
Does it hurt?
很疼吗？
You think that hurts?
你觉得很疼吗？
Soo-hyun was
秀贤
only five years old.
才五岁
-I was going to ask for money. -What money?
-我本来想要钱的 -什么钱？
-I was going to ask for two million won. -What?
-我本来想要两百万韩元 -什么？
I wanted a ransom.
我想要赎金
Two million won?
两百万韩元？
Let us interview him too.
让我们也采访他吧
Keep it down.
小点声
Hey, I'll let you interview him
喂 等他被转到
before he gets transferred to the prosecution.
检察院之前我让你采访他
You just wait for now.
你先等等
-You're just going to transfer him, right? -No.
-你准备直接把他转走 是不是？ -不是
Yes, you will. Come on.
就是的 你就是这么想的 拜托啊
We must find out
我们一定要找到
where the other two fingers are.
另外两根手指在哪里
I was just going to ask for money at first. I'm telling the truth.
我本来是准备要钱的 我说的是真的
But what?
后来呢？
-Mom. -Hey.
-妈妈 -喂
-Mom! -Don't cry. Why are you crying?
-别哭了 你哭什么？
Mom.
妈妈
-Darn it. -Mom.
-该死 -妈妈
Good work, Captain Yoon.
辛苦了 尹组长
Let's go.
走吧
Cho Hyun-gil kidnapped a five-year-old girl, Lee Soo-hyun.
赵贤吉绑架了五岁女童李秀贤
Hey, kid.
小朋友
Do you want me to buy you ice cream?
你想不想让我给你买冰激凌吃？
This one.
要这个
He was going to demand a ransom of two million won.
他原本准备索要两百万韩元赎金
But Lee Soo-hyun got scared
但李秀贤因害怕
and couldn't remember her parents' phone number.
记不起父母电话
He forced her to drink water spiked with sleeping pills.
他就强迫她喝下掺了安眠药的水
And the five-year-old girl, Lee Soo-hyun, was…
将五岁女童李秀贤…
AND THE 5-YEAR-OLD GIRL, LEE SOO HYUN, WAS…
（将五岁女童李秀贤强…）
Why did you do it?
你为什么要杀人？
Can I…
我…
smoke a cigarette?
可以抽根烟吗？
You scumbag. How dare you ask for a cigarette?
你这个人渣 还敢要烟？
No, you can't.
不 你不能抽
Mr. Cho Hyun-gil.
赵贤吉
How do you feel right now?
你现在是什么感受？
-I'm sorry. -To whom?
-我很愧疚 -对谁？
He's asking you to whom you're apologizing, you jerk!
他问你对谁愧疚 你这混蛋
-Sir. -You scumbag.
-队长 -你这个人渣
Let go of me. That jerk…
别拉我 那个混蛋…
Are you trying to cooperate or what?
你还想不想合作了？
What?
什么？
Don't interrupt us or provoke him.
不要打断我们 也不要激怒他
But I'm furious!
可是我快气死了
How could you not be after looking at him?
你看到他之后怎么能不生气呢？
You know my second child's name is Soo-hyun, right?
你知道我家老二的名字就叫秀贤吧？
-And she's six years old. -Exactly.
-她六岁了 -所以啊
That's why you must be infuriated right now.
所以你现在一定非常气愤
Don't come in. Stay out here.
别进来了 在外边待着
-Hey. I… -I'm asking you.
-喂 我… -我求你了
Please.
拜托你
How did you lose your fingers?
你的手指怎么断的？
It happened when I was working.
工作的时候断的
Both of them?
两根都是吗？
Yes.
是的
When did it happen?
什么时候的事？
I was 30.
我30岁的时候
It was an accident at a construction site.
在建筑工地上发生了事故
-Why didn't you reattach your fingers? -My fingers flew out.
-为什么没把手指接回去？ -我的手指飞出去了
I searched for hours.
我找了好几个小时
But I was bleeding a lot.
而且流了很多血
In the end, I couldn't find them.
最后也没找到
I was at a construction site, so I didn't know where they went.
当时是在建筑工地上 所以我也不知道到底掉哪了
You must have been in pain.
你一定很痛苦
-Yes. -Are you ashamed…
-是的 -你是否…
that you're missing fingers?
为失去手指感到羞耻？
I feel like people treat me like I'm retarded.
我觉得别人看我像看弱智一样
And women don't like that about you, right?
女人也不喜欢你的断指 是吗？
We already caught the fish.
我们已经抓到鱼了
Will that even help?
那么做有用吗？
We should think about slicing it or grilling it.
应该把鱼切片或者烤了
-I'll erase this. -Leave it.
-我把这个擦了 -别动
The Behavioral Analysis Team is still working on it.
犯罪行为分析组还在处理
"We already caught the fish"?
“我们已经抓到鱼了”？
Are we here to fish?
我们是来钓鱼的吗？
I mean…
我是说…
I'll be more careful.
我以后会注意的
By the way,
对了
we have to wait until they're done, right?
我们还要等他们弄完 是吗？
I'm just curious.
我就是好奇
I wonder what they are talking about.
我想知道他们在聊什么
But kids aren't like that.
可孩子不会
Even if you don't have fingers,
就算你没有手指
they still approach you because they are innocent.
天真的他们也愿意亲近你
Right.
是的
Kids are nice.
孩子们很善良
Then how could you…
那你怎么能…
Is that why you got rid of…
你是因此才把秀贤的两只手指
two of Soo-hyun's fingers too?
砍下来了吗？
On the 12th,
12日
the police apprehended the culprit behind the mutilated girl
警方逮捕了在彰义洞发现的
that was found in Changeui-dong.
被肢解女童的幕后凶手
Chief Heo Gil-pyo of the Special Crime Squad
首尔地方警察厅
at the Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency
机搜队队长许吉票
stated that the culprit was Cho
发表声明称凶手赵某
who lived around where the body parts were found in Changeui-dong.
居住在彰义洞发现尸块地点的附近
And the police requested an arrest warrant for murder and abandonment of a corpse.
警方已申请逮捕令 罪名是谋杀抛尸
Severed body parts were found in Changeui-dong, Bumyeong-dong,
被切割的身体分别在彰义洞、富明洞
and at a motel in Gyeongseong-dong.
还有庆成洞的一家旅馆被发现
But the police stated that
但警方称
two of the girl's fingers could not be found.
女童的两根手指暂未找到
Cho had already served two years and six months in prison
赵某曾在1997年因强奸未成年人
for sexually assaulting a minor in 1997.
被判两年零六个月
The police also confirmed Cho's past criminal record.
警方也确认了赵某的历史服刑记录
The police will transfer Cho
调查结束后
to the prosecution once the investigation is complete.
赵某将由警方转交给检方
-You jerk! -You scumbag!
-混蛋 -人渣
-How could you do that? -Bring her back!
-你怎么能做这种事？ -把她还给我
-You scumbag! -How could you?
-人渣 -你怎么可以？
-You're evil! -Murderer!
-魔鬼 -杀人犯
-You jerk! -Scumbag!
-混蛋 -人渣
-You murderer! -How could you kill her?
-杀人犯 -你怎么下得了手杀她？
-You evil murderer! -Bring her back!
-把她还给我
You scumbag!
人渣
-You're not human! -You!
-你不是人 -你
Her fingers never turned up.
她的手指再也没找到
ALLEYWAY DINER
（小巷餐厅）
Even after committing such a heinous crime,
即使犯下那么令人发指的罪行
he didn't show any sense of remorse!
他还是没有半点自责
How is that possible?
怎么会这样呢？
He apologized,
他是道歉了
but he didn't apologize to anyone in particular.
可他的道歉没有针对任何人
How is that possible?
怎么会这样呢？
-Gosh. -You should go easy on that.
-天啊 -你少喝点
That little girl
那个小女孩
was the target because she was nice.
是因为善良才被选中了
-Her fingers… -I'll get going first.
-她的手指… -我先走了
Okay. Go.
好 你走吧
Please take care of him.
请照顾好他
Okay. I'll make sure he gets home safely.
好 我会送他安全回家的
NO DRUNK DRIVING
（严禁醉驾）
FAMILY APARTMENTS
（家庭公寓）
Mom, why are you crying?
妈妈 你怎么哭了？
Why are you crying, Mom? Don't cry.
你怎么哭了 妈妈？别哭了
I'm sorry…
对不起…
I won't cry.
我不哭了
"Wrong desires directed at a child"?
“针对儿童的错误本能”？
Gosh, are they crazy?
天啊 他们是疯了吗？
Crime is the result of one's desire?
犯罪是人的本能？
IM MOO-SIK, DAEHAN DAILY
（《大韩日报》林武植记者）
Im Moo-sik?
林武植？
RAPE AND MUTILATION MURDER OF A 5-YEAR-OLD GIRL
（五岁女童强奸肢解谋杀案）
Upload the article quickly.
快点上传报道
Okay, I will.
好 知道了
Are we living in a world where good kids can feel safe?
我们生活的世界 还能让善良的孩子们感到安全吗？
Maybe what we lost
也许我们失去的
is a lot more than a child who was like an angel.
远远不是一个天使般的孩子那么简单
Maybe humanity and the belief that we must be good are also lost.
也许失去的还有善良的人性和信仰
Cho Hyun-gil had committed a crime against a child in the past,
赵贤吉曾犯下侵犯儿童的罪行
but he was released back to society without turning over a new leaf.
却在尚未改过自新时被送回社会
Who is responsible for creating a world like this?
创造出这种世界是哪个大人的责任？
Perhaps, the only thing we can do
也许我们唯一能做的
is remember the short life of Lee, the little girl who died,
就是记住曾短暂停留在人世的小女孩
and truly lament
真诚地为她的逝去
and grieve her death.
默哀并哀悼
Happy birthday to you
祝你生日快乐
Happy birthday, dear Soo-hyun
祝你生日快乐 亲爱的秀贤
5:38 P.M.
（1999年7月16日下午5点38分）
I want a four-wheeler.
我想要一辆四轮车
1:06 P.M.
（1999年12月24日下午1点06分）
Soo-hyun, who do you like more? Mom or Dad?
秀贤 你更喜欢妈妈还是爸爸？
I love you both!
两个都爱
2:42 P.M.
（2000年3月5日下午2点42分）
I love you too, Soo-hyun.
我也爱你 秀贤
I'm home.
我回来了
Hey, you're getting in late.
喂 你回来晚了
Why are you still up?
你怎么还没睡？
I couldn't fall asleep.
我睡不着
You know, that kid's case.
你知道的 那个孩子的案子
Wasn't it what you were working on?
是你负责的吧？
-Yes. -Are you all right?
-是的 -你还好吗？
Yes, of course.
当然没事
Here, have some.
给 吃点这个吧
I noticed that you'd run out.
我看到你吃完了
You no longer need to worry about me. I'm an adult.
你不用再替我操心了 我是成年人了
I'm not worried.
我没担心
Get some sleep.
去睡吧
This is exactly why I get worried.
所以我才会担心啊
When you were little, you just fell into my arms and cried.
小时候还会扑到我怀里大哭一场
ALLEYWAY DINER
（小巷餐厅）
Gosh, careful.
天啊 小心
Hey, I'm really okay.
喂 我真没事
I'm totally sober right now.
我现在非常清醒
-Still, I'll take you home. -No need.
-我还是送你回去吧 -不用
Captain Kook Young-soo is fine.
国荣秀组长没事
Hey, Jung Woo-ju.
喂 郑宇宙
Jung Woo-ju. Jung Chu Chu.
郑宇宙 郑宇宙宙
Hey, your name is as unusual as mine.
喂 你的名字跟我的一样与众不同
Jung Chu Chu.
郑宇宙宙
-Bye. Don't worry about me. -But…
-再见 不用担心我 -可是…
Get home safely, sir.
你慢走
What are you up to? Let's grab a drink together.
你在干吗？一起喝一杯吧
I'm not in the mood for a drink.
我没心情
Maybe another time.
下次吧
Gosh, I'm totally in the mood for a drink right now,
天啊 我正是想喝酒的心情
but I guess Woo-ju isn't.
可是宇宙不想
Have you adjusted to your position?
你调整好自己的位置了吗？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊？
I'm really struggling.
我真的很纠结
-Young-soo, where are you now? -You know,
-荣秀 你现在在哪儿？ -你知道不知道
when I see our boys rip out a piece of paper
这么热的天气 我们组的孩子们
to use it as a fan in this sweltering heat,
抽出一张纸当扇子用
it really breaks my heart.
那时候我有多难过
I'll ask for an AC unit.
我会申请空调的
We don't even have a table where we can sit down and eat together.
我们连坐下一起吃顿饭的餐桌都没有
I'll ask for that too.
这个我也会申请的
A big table.
一张大桌子
It'll be winter before you know it.
马上就到冬天了
Do we even have a heater? Of course, we don't have one.
我们有电热器吗？肯定没有
As if you can hold out that long anyway…
你们能撑到那时候就…
Anyway, just hang up and go home.
算了 赶紧挂了回家去吧
Why is everyone so worried about me getting home?
为什么大家都这么关心让我回家？
I'm not the one you should be worried about.
我不是你应该关心的人
You know that.
你知道的
It's not me, you know?
不是我 你知道吗？
Goodness.
真是的
Excuse me.
抱歉
She became the target
她是因为善良
because she was nice.
才被选中的
That's right.
没错
The police…
警察…
The only thing we can do is…
我们唯一能做的就是…
I'm sorry.
对不起
I apologize.
我道歉
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
Good morning, Chief Heo.
早上好啊 许队长
I guess you managed to get home safely.
看来你安全到家了啊
Of course. Did you think I'd die on the street or something?
当然了 你以为我会横死街头吗？
As if. Even the fortune-teller said you wouldn't die so easily.
才怪 连算命先生都说你命大
So the fortune-teller wouldn't want you to die like that.
所以算命先生不会让你那么容易死的
And you know that I never black out when I drink, right?
先不管什么死不死的 你知道我喝酒从来不会断片 对吧？
Keep on bragging.
接着吹
An AC unit, a table, and a heater.
空调 餐桌 还有电热器
I remember everything.
我什么都记得
-Get out of my way. -Look.
-别挡我的路 -听我说
I told you that he'd be perfect for the job
我跟你说过他是这个工作的完美人选
and that he'd help us identify the culprit.
他能帮我们找到凶手
The suspect is missing two fingers, right?
凶手缺了两根手指 对吧？
We were right about everything.
我们全都猜对了
Am I wrong?
我没说错吧？
So why can't you trust us?
你为什么不相信我们呢？
Have I ever said anything that proved to be wrong?
我说过的话什么出错过？
No, right?
从来没有 对吧？
-You should get going. -Yes, I should.
-你赶紧走吧 -是 我会走的
An AC unit, a table, and a heater. I won't wait too long.
空调 餐桌 电热器 别让我等太久
What do you want for lunch?
你中午想吃什么？
Jjajangmyeon.
炸酱面
BRUTAL CRIME AND CHILD'S DEATH, WHAT MUST WE REMEMBER?
（残忍罪行和儿童之殇 我们应该记住什么？）
REPORTER CHOI YOON-JI, FACT TODAY
（《今日真相》记者崔润智）
Don't you know how to drive?
你会开车吗？
What were you thinking?
你在想什么呢？
-Gosh. -Did you get hurt?
-真是的 -你受伤了吗？
My gosh.
天啊
Just a moment, please.
稍等
Excuse me, but could you give me your hand for a moment?
不好意思 你能把手给我一下吗？
What?
什么？
I don't have a business card.
我没带名片
Call that number if anything happens.
有事就打那个号码
Handle it through your insurance since you took pictures already.
既然你拍过照了 就先让保险公司处理吧
I have an urgent matter to get to. My apologies.
我还有急事 不好意思
Where do you think you're going?
你想逃去哪里啊？
I'm sorry but I really have an urgent matter to get to.
不好意思 不过我真的是有急事
Handle it through insurance and call that number if there are any issues.
让保险公司处理吧 有事打那个号码
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Hey, wait.
等等
This is my number.
这是我的电话
REPORTER CHOI YOON-JI, FACT TODAY
（《今日真相》记者崔润智）
-Hello, sir! -Hello.
-你好
Good morning.
早上好
What are you reading?
你在看什么？
It's just an article.
一篇报道
REPORTER CHOI YOON-JI
（崔润智记者）
She's doing pretty well.
她写得很好
-Hello. -Hi.
-你好
-Are you all right? -Of course.
-你还好吗？ -当然了
My gosh. How in the world did the Behavioral Analysis Team
天啊 犯罪行为分析小组
land a smart one like you?
怎么会有你这么机灵的人啊？
Listen carefully.
听好了
They will give us an AC unit.
他们要给我们一台空调
There's more.
还有呢
-More? -Yes.
-还有？ -没错
A table?
餐桌？
-And there's one more. -One more?
-还有 -还有？
-Guess what. -What is it?
-猜猜是什么 -是什么？
A heater for winter.
冬天用的电热器
Does that means we'll continue to stay here and not in the main building?
那是不是说我们要继续在这里 不能去主楼？
I didn't think about it that way. Shall I tell them to forgo the heater?
我没往那方面想 我要不要让他们别弄电热器了？
What's the problem? I like this place.
怎么了？我还挺喜欢这里的
You've gotten used to this place too, haven't you?
你也开始习惯这里了 是不是？
It's all right here.
这里还不错
-Let's ask for the heater. -Yes, sir.
-跟他们要个电热器 -好
Now what?
现在怎么办？
Just give them what they want. All of it.
他们要什么就给什么吧 都给他们
We have to give them what's necessary.
我们得把必需品给他们啊
It's nothing special anyway.
又不是什么稀奇东西
That's not the problem right now though.
不过现在问题不是那个
Kook Young-soo, that guy, gave up his position as Chief of Forensics
国荣秀那家伙放弃鉴定股长的位置
to start a Behavioral Analysis Team or whatever it is.
组建犯罪行为分析小组什么的
I get that he used to be the godfather down at Forensics.
我明白他以前是鉴定科元老
But that only matters if he's still in the squad.
可那个身份只有他还在科里才算数
He's just a nobody to everyone else.
否则对其他人来说他就是无名小卒
And what about that guy, Song Ha-young?
还有另外那个家伙 宋霞永
What was the point of promoting him?
晋升他干什么呢？
Rumors about how he almost lost his job from the Red Cap Incident
到处都在传 他差点因为红帽子事件被炒鱿鱼
and how this is a failed team have spread everywhere.
还有流言蜚语称这是个废物团队
We're to blame for how that rumor started though.
那种流言还不是从我们这儿传出去的
So we should be taking responsibility for it!
所以我们得为他们负责啊
What if their team disappears?
万一他们小组没了呢？
Where will those two go? They're too old for the job market.
那两个家伙能去哪儿？ 年纪那么大也不好找工作了
Shouldn't we put them to work and evaluate them first
不管能不能做出成绩 总该让他们
before we decide on whether they'll put out results or not?
先干点活儿 评估一下吧？
Gosh, I know! I'm aware of that too.
天啊 我知道 我也明白那个道理
Just give them some time for now.
先给他们一点时间
How much time? This is so frustrating.
多少时间？真是发愁
I already asked the higher-ups
我已经向上边申请过
to at least give them some time to interview criminals
至少给他们点时间去采访犯人
and gather data on criminal types.
收集犯罪类型的数据
You did?
是吗？
What are the higher-ups saying?
上边怎么说？
For this Cho Hyun-gil case,
对于本次赵贤吉案
the Behavioral Analysis Team fulfilled their part
犯罪行为分析组协助我们
by helping us narrow down the list of suspects.
缩小嫌疑人范围 尽职尽责
Do you think we have an open-ended budget?
你以为我们有用不完的预算吗？
You know how they are.
你知道他们什么样
They always groan and complain
总是埋怨个不停
about how we don't even have enough to work in the field.
说去现场的人手都不够
Goodness.
天啊
It's because you're too soft.
还不是因为你太软弱了
This is why I can't quit smoking.
所以我才戒不了烟
It's cinnamon-flavored candy? Darn it.
还是肉桂味的糖？该死
Choi Yoon-ji was always a bit different back in school too.
崔润智以前在学校就有点与众不同
I guess you can say that's her strength too.
也可以说是她的优点
No, of course not.
不 当然不是
I'm grateful she chose to work here.
我很感恩她选择来这里工作
Yes, I'm grateful.
对 我很感恩
But I still need to make a living.
不过我也得生活的
What's the use of being a conscious reporter when the media is crumbling down?
整个新闻界都乱成一团的时候 做个有良知的记者有什么用呢？
Yes, that's right.
好 知道了
Stop talking about it and put it into action.
别说了赶紧行动吧
-Is your hangover bad? -I'm all right.
-胃还好吗？ -我没事
Do you even remember drunk dialing me yesterday and harassing me,
你还记得昨晚发酒疯 给我打电话骚扰我
saying how miserable you are?
说你多悲惨吗？
I didn't say that because I was drunk.
我说那话不是醉话
I get it. It wasn't an easy case.
我明白 那个案子不简单
Good job. You did well.
做得好 你写得很好
But this isn't just about appealing to the readers' emotions.
但能不能不去试图引发读者的共情？
You see, a reporter…
你要知道一个记者…
That's enough advice for today, Director.
局长 你能不能就说前面半句？
What's with the "but"?
为什么后面又有转折啊？
Why do you think so?
你觉得呢？
That's my role, you rascal.
那是我的职责啊 你这个丫头
Let's go cure your hangover.
去醒醒酒吧
I need to get going in a bit.
我马上要出去一趟
At least get a bite before you leave.
走之前至少先喝点汤
You'll upset your stomach.
不然胃会不舒服的
Okay, I'll eat before I go.
好 我走之前会吃东西的
Aren't we done since we caught him?
既然抓到他了 我们就结束了吧？
Even if everyone else thinks that way, we have to think about what comes after.
就算别人都那么想 我们也要考虑后续该怎么做
-After this? -Yes.
-后续？ -对
-Analyzing the mind. -"Analyzing the mind"?
-分析思想 -“分析思想”？
It's true that criminal profiling
犯罪侧写确实
is used in order to catch the culprit.
是用来抓住凶手的
But what comes after that is important too.
可是后续也很重要
What does that have to do with analyzing the mind?
那和分析思想有什么关系？
It's not over when we catch the culprit.
抓住凶手还不算结束
There will always be another one who appears.
永远会有下一个凶手出现
Hold on.
等等
You said you were going to speak comfortably to me.
你说过你准备和我说话随意一点的
Did I say that?
我说过吗？
I'll speak comfortably to you if you don't do it first.
如果你不说 我就先说了
Since you've brought it up, you go ahead and do that.
既然是你提起来的 就先从你开始吧
Should I do that then?
我可以这样吗？
Captain Yoon!
尹组长
Over here, Captain Yoon! Come sit here.
过来 尹组长 来坐这边
-We'll sit over there with them. -Okay.
-去那边和他们坐一起吧 -好
We just need to bring a chair over.
再拉把椅子过来就行了
We just got started eating too, so join us.
我们也刚开始吃 一起吧
Yes, please join us.
对 一起吃吧
-Two more orders of the set please, ma'am! -Got it!
-老板 这桌再来两份 -好
Please excuse us then.
那就打扰你们了
What's there to excuse?
说什么打扰啊？
We're all on the same team.
我们都是一条船上的
Carry on with your conversation.
你们继续聊
It seems like we interrupted it.
好像被我们打断了啊
Whether criminals who committed serious crimes can be
犯下严重罪行的罪犯
rehabilitated in prison or not.
能不能在监狱里被重新改造
Or if the rehabilitation program needs some sort of change.
改造流程是否需要某种变革
Or if there is a chance of recidivism.
是否有再犯的可能性
We have to figure those things out. That's what we were talking about.
要弄清楚这些事情 我们刚才就在聊这些
Cho Hyun-gil committed the same crime after just two months of being released.
赵贤吉出狱才两个月就再犯了
That's why you want to interview Cho Hyun-gil!
原来你想采访赵贤吉是因为这个
What? You're interviewing Cho Hyun-gil again?
什么？你们又在采访赵贤吉？
There's a lot we have to ask him.
我们要问他的问题还多着呢
Not only is he our team's first case,
不仅因为他是我们小组的第一个案子
but if we want to write our report on criminal psychology analysis,
我们还想写犯罪心理分析报告
I think we'll have to meet him at least once more.
我觉得我们至少还要再跟他见一次
This team is always working very hard.
这个小组总是那么勤奋
If we want people to know
如果我们想让人们知道
that the Behavioral Analysis Team contributes to catching the culprit,
犯罪行为分析组对抓犯人有帮助
-we have to work harder. -We have to show it's not interest
-我们还要再勤奋一点 -我们要让大家看到激励我们的
that motivates us, but our sense of duty instead.
不是单纯的猎奇 而是我们的责任感
It may just be an intriguing case to you and your team,
对你和你的团队来说 做这个案子可能只是猎奇
but my team has a duty to solve it.
对我的团队来说 破案才是职责所在
Whatever the case,
无论如何
more heinous criminals will show up.
还会有更多重案犯出现的
I hope my guess is wrong. I'd be happy if I'm wrong.
我希望我的猜想是错的 如果我错了 我会很开心的
But there still has to be someone preparing for what may happen.
但仍然需要有人 时刻准备着应对未知情况
Thank you!
谢谢你
We have more than enough already.
重案已经够多了
Just how much more heinous will they get for us to need to prepare?
还会有多少啊 需要我们做好准备？
Daesung Serial Murder Case.
大成连环杀人案
That punk. We even released his montage but why won't he get caught?
那个混蛋 我们连他的模拟画像 都公布了 怎么还抓不到他？
Those punks that commit serial murders
那些实施连环谋杀的混蛋
aren't in the range of normal that we think of.
不属于我们认为的一般罪犯
It's hard to track them down the way we normally do.
按照常规方法很难抓到他们
What do you mean, it's hard to track them down
“按照常规方法很难抓到他们”
the way we normally do?
这是什么意思？
If we look at the pattern of a crime,
从犯罪模式来看
we can tell to an extent whether it was resentment or blind passion.
我们能判断是仇杀情杀 还是为了钱
That's right. It's clear as day.
没错 很容易看出来
But when it's none of these…
可如果这些都不是…
Guys who commit crimes randomly and recklessly.
随机冲动杀人的家伙
We can't read their behavior patterns. Why is that?
我们很难解读他们的行为模式 为什么？
Because they don't belong to any category.
因为他们不属于任何一种类型
Are you saying that's the case with the Daesung Serial Murder Case?
你是说大成连环杀人案就是这种？
That's right.
没错
Once our team settles down…
等我们团队稳定下来…
He's the first one I want to catch.
我第一个想抓的就是他
He'll be caught before that.
不用等到那时候就能抓到他
Even though he stopped,
虽然他停手了
our investigation will continue.
我们还会继续调查
Yes, he has to be caught.
对 一定要抓住他
He's the most wanted criminal by the Korean police.
他是韩国警察最想抓的犯人
Please excuse me.
我先走了
Wait for us. We're almost done too.
等一下 我们也快吃好了
It's okay. You can take your time to eat.
没事 你们慢慢吃
Please excuse me.
我先走了
-It's on me. Just go. -Thank you.
-我来请 你走吧 -谢谢你
Goodness. He is always so predictable.
天啊 他永远都是这个样子
Goodness.
真是的
UNRESOLVED CASE FILES, 1991
（悬案档案 1991年）
DAESUNG SERIAL MURDER CASE
（大成连环谋杀案）
Anyway, what does that have to do with a potentially atrocious case?
可是那和意外的惨案有什么关系？
Listen up.
听着
In the US, heinous criminals who only seek to murder
美国经历最大的经济变革后
began to surface during their biggest economic change.
只为杀人的重案犯就开始冒出来了
There's a report on the correlation.
这之间的关联是有报告依据的
That's why we must be prepared.
所以我们一定要做好准备
Anyhow,
不管怎么说
Daesung Serial Murder Case was way too shocking for me,
大成连环谋杀案都让我无比震惊
so I studied it extensively.
所以我广泛研究了这个案子
After I saw the cases from overseas, I realized they're like smart criminals.
看到国外的案例后 我发现他们就像高智商罪犯一样
Their brains are wired only to murder.
他们的大脑只和谋杀联系在一起
That's why their MO and patterns evolve over time.
所以他们的作案手法和模式 会随着时间进化
NONGSU-RO, HYUNGSAN-RI
（亨山里 农秀路）
Here's what I mean.
我是这个意思
The atrocity of their murder and their crimes
他们杀人的强度和快乐的程度
will be taken to an extreme.
会直接到达高潮
That's why they change the patterns in an attempt to flee from us.
所以他们会改变模式试图躲过我们
When they change the pattern and the MO,
如果他们改变模式和作案手法
catching them will be even harder.
就会越来越难抓住他们
If we do not get prepared,
如果我们不做好准备
we'll see another cold case like the Daesung serial murders.
会出现和大成连环谋杀案类似的惨案
-I see. -It'd be wonderful if it doesn't happen.
-明白了 -最好不要发生这种事情
I'm just trying to be prepared, for just ten years.
我想只用十年时间做好准备
I want to put in some work
我想只用十年时间投入努力
Then will our team last for ten years?
那我们的团队只能存在十年吗？
-Can you do this? -Yes, I can, sir.
-你愿意吗？ -我愿意 组长
Anyway, thank you for listening to my boring story.
谢谢你们听我啰嗦这么久
Lunch is on me.
午饭我请了
-No, it's all right. -Thank you so much for lunch.
-不 没事的 -非常感谢招待午饭
Goodness.
真是
I have finally gone insane.
我终究是疯了
-What's wrong? -My wallet.
-怎么了？ -钱包
-I'll pay. -No.
-我来付吧 -不
That's not what I meant.
我不是那个意思
Captain Yoon.
-尹组长 -谢谢你
Captain Yoon, something he said has been bugging me.
尹组长 他说的话让我一直很不爽
What is?
什么话？
No matter how crazy we are, we have to say the right things.
就算再疯狂 说话也要凭良心啊
To be frank, we caught Cho Hyun-gil.
说实话是我们抓住赵贤吉的
Okay, I give them credit for analyzing him and stuff.
是 他们分析心理什么的也立了功
But so what?
那又怎么样？
It's not like we don't try to guess what the culprit is like.
我们又不是没猜过凶手的样子
We just can't be right all the time.
只是我们没有百发百中罢了
And if you think about it, the same goes for that team.
而且你想想看 那个小组也是
They somehow ended up guessing Cho Hyun-gil right.
他们莫名其妙猜中了赵贤吉
They can't say they took part in…
不能就这么说他们参与了…
That's mine.
那是我的
Why? Did they say they caught Cho Hyun-gil?
怎么了？ 他们说是他们抓住了赵贤吉吗？
No, it's not like that.
不 不是的
I knew they'd get cheeky.
我就知道他们会骄傲的
I told you not to let them take credit.
我跟你说过别让他们分一杯羹
They should be grateful they still have a job.
他们还有活干已经谢天谢地了
Everyone knows about the Red Cap Incident.
谁不知道红帽子事件
People in this field are unbelievably talkative.
干这行的人真是话太多了
We're the ones who ran around doing the footwork.
跑来跑去当苦力的人是我们啊
-Isn't that so? -Stop it already.
-我说的没错吧？ -不要说了
Are we here to play a game of dart?
我们是来玩飞镖游戏的吗？
Trying to be infallible in getting things right.
把事情做好的同时也要做到可靠
I don't appreciate the expressions you've been using recently, okay?
我不喜欢你最近总说这种话 好吗？
I…
我…
Okay. I'll be careful.
好 我会注意的
Try to think things over before you say them out loud.
说话前先想清楚
Yes, ma'am.
知道了
Finish your coffee and come.
喝完咖啡来找我
What's with her?
她这是怎么了？
You owe me 200 won.
你欠我200韩元
DAESUNG SERIAL MURDER CASE
（大成连环谋杀案）
SERIAL MURDER CASE
（连环谋杀案）
Please relax your shoulders.
请放松肩膀
All right. Look into the camera.
好 看镜头
I'll take the photo now.
我要按快门了
Smile.
笑一笑
The train is approaching.
列车即将进站
Please step back from the safety line.
请退回安全线后
ID PHOTO
（证件照）
SENIOR INSPECTOR KOOK YOUNG-SOO
（警监 国荣秀）
You can relax.
你放心
I'm the police.
我是警察
Right.
好
It's dangerous for a woman to go around alone at night.
女性夜晚独自走夜路很危险
Thank you.
谢谢你
Let me escort you.
我护送你吧
I'm fine, but sure.
没事的 谢谢你
Let's go.
走吧
Did you dress up to see me? I feel special.
你是专门为我打扮的吗？受宠若惊
You want to hear my story?
想听我的故事？
-Like what? -You can tell us about you childhood
-比如呢？ -你可以告诉我们你的童年
or about what you usually feel.
或者你平时的感受
We need you to take on a case.
我们需要你接一个案子
He and his wife were murdered in their home two weeks ago.
两周前他们夫妻俩在家中遇害
We weren't able to identify what he hit them with yet.
我们还没能找到他作案时的凶器
-There's another one. -Another case broke out.
-又有一个 -又出现一个案子
This one is from Suseong-dong, Gangnam.
这个是在江南区寿城洞
-And this one is from Gungok-dong, Jongno. -Don't these look similar?
-这个是在钟路区郡谷洞 -看起来是不是很像？
Who on earth is this guy? The MO is the same.
这家伙到底是谁？作案手法都一样
This is the third murder, and his only purpose is to kill.
这是第三起谋杀案 他的唯一目的就是杀人
It's a serial murder.
这是一个连环杀人案